# UWEM AKPABOT

**FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** 

Email: mr.akpabot@gmail.com Phone: +234 816-266-5633

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/uwem-akpabot/

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Greenwich, UK

M.Sc. Software Engineering (2012-2013)

## University of Calabar, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science (2005-2009)

#### **CORE EXPERTISE**

- Python programming
- Django, DRF, RESTful API
- Java programming
- React.js JavaScript programming
- PHP (and Laravel), HTML, CSS
- Agile (Scrum), SDLC, OOP, MVC
- Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Testing Selenium, Pytest, Jest
- Data Structures and Algorithms

#### **SKILLS**

- Technical writing and Research
- Problem-solving skills
- Good team player
- Attention to detail
- Excellent communication
- Project management
- Leadership and organization

#### **CERTIFICATION**

• Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)

#### **SUMMARY**

A highly skilled Full-Stack Software Developer with 5+ years of experience, earned an MSc. Software Engineering from the UK. I am seeking an opportunity to work on different projects in an excellent work environment, to collaborate and be part of a multicultural team. Eager to develop applications and tools for data sharing platforms, and software systems that meet users' requirements, that are easy to use, easier to modify, and perform flawlessly.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full-Stack Software Developer First Samone/Luday AB, Sweden (Feb 2022 - Apr 2024)

- Designed and developed software systems for commercial clients including ecommerce websites using Python/React.js.
- Collected users' requirements, designed new features, wrote reliable and efficient code. Worked closely with stakeholders and team members to ensure high quality and user satisfaction.
- Managed projects from initial concept through deployment and maintenance, ensuring on-time and on-budget delivery
- Coordinated and orchestrated projects, responsible for the software design, led three software teams, performed code reviews, provided feedback, and mentored interns to success.

## Senior Software Developer/Instructor ICA Specs, Ltd., Nigeria (Jan 2014 - Dec 2018)

- Our team of four developers designed and developed a robust school software (OSIMS), we also completed a Health software (HISA), and I mentored intern software developers.
- Senior Programming Instructor Web Design, PHP, and Python

### Software Developer (Short term contract) FHI 360, Abuja, Nigeria (Aug 2015 - Nov 2015)

• Extended the features of iHRIS health software; added Training and Calendar modules for M&E Department.

### Web Developer GCL Hub, Lagos, Nigeria (Jul 2013 - Mar 2014)

 Planned, designed, developed, tested, and deployed websites for clients, and for GCL at https://gclhub.com

#### MSC. DISSERTATION TOPIC

 Use of Software Design to Develop an Airline Service Application for Travelers (Published in 2013)